Jeroen Peeters

Software Engineer / Technical Lead

jeroen@peetersweb.nl

Summary

All-round software engineer and technical lead with extensive experience with development stacks such as Java (Enterprise), C/C++ (Embedded), Android/React Native (Mobile). Always expanding my horizon with new and interesting tools and languages such as NodeJS, Meteor, React and Kotlin. Currently focusing on Docker and Continuous Delivery & Deployment. Big fan of quality metrics to continuously drive improvements. Promoter of agile processes such as Scrum and Kanban. Strong technical skills. Passionate speaker. Always ready to learn something new.

Experience

Software Engineer & Technical Lead at ICTU

June 2017 - Present

As a member of the core team I help and guide projects in the world of continuous delivery, software quality assurance and agile development processes. I help them to resolve any impediments they may encounter along the way. Furthermore I help clients and hosting parties to integrate the team's output into their environments, extending the continuous delivery experience.

Software Engineer/IT Professional at OVSoftware

August 2012 - Present

IT consultancy services for various governmental organizations and agencies in the region of The Hague.

Owner

September 2006 - Present

TwoMendDesign provides services to boost your company's succes by providing better internet applications. We design and develop websites and internet applications. We aim to provide one complete package to our customers, including hosting services.

I am responsible for the Software Development department within TwoMenDesign.

Software Engineer at ICTU

August 2012 - June 2017 (4 years 11 months)

Within ICTU I fulfill the role of all-round Software Engineer. Initially I started as a Java Software Engineer on the Bulk Inspection Data Provisioning System and Generic Connection Facility. After that I moved to the RNI project. Main technologies used by these projects are Java, Spring, Seam/JSF, Hadoop and JBoss. These projects have a more detailed description down below.

Currently I'm working on the Innovation and Quality team where we cultivate new technologies to empower all other projects to do Continuous Integration and Delivery. We do this using Docker, Automated Regression Test Tooling and Software Quality Monitoring. Tooling to make this possible is developed inhouse, such as a dashboard for Docker to ease the composition and maintainability of applications.

Software Developer at Collis (currently known as UL Transaction Security)

January 2008 - August 2012 (4 years 8 months)

I have contributed to the development of Collis' in-house tools like the Visa payWave Test Tool, Collis Brand Test Tool and the Collis Card Simulator. All of these tools, and many more, are based on the application framework I've developed during my thesis. Maintaining and extending the framework is also one of my responsibilities.

Furthermore I take care of software life cycle management (bugfixes, patches, releases), continuous software integration and technical customer support.

Thesis

Architecture, design and implementation of a test tool application framework.

Software Engineer at Ministerie van Veiligheid en Justitie

June 2010 - June 2012 (2 years 1 month)

Software design and implementation for multiple independently operating software agents in order to realize the PKI infrastrucure for ePassports. The agents are deployed on a layered server architecture, each layer having a different level of automated behavior.

Hired through Collis.

Software Engineer at RDW

January 2011 - February 2011 (2 months)

Development of a data preparation service solution used to perform batch orders and create the structured personalisation information for driving license applets on a chip card.

Hired through Collis.

Software Developer

October 2003 - June 2008 (4 years 9 months)

Website and webapplication development. Asteco focusses on commercial web applications such as custom build cms and webshop application.

Asteco also provides webhosting services.

I was responsible for development and maintenance of web applications and websites.

Software Developer - internship at Collis (currently known as UL Transaction Security)

August 2007 - January 2008 (6 months)

During this internship I worked on two separate projects in order to fulfill the requirements of the HBO Informatics bachelor degree.

I worked on software to edit smart card images in a proprietary XML format specifically designed for the German Healthcard project - EGK. These smart card images are used to emulate smart card applications and therefore make it easier to test a variety of different scenario's using both simulated as real hardware.

Secondly I worked on the Collis Brand Test Tool. This is a tool to test if a payment terminal (POS or ATM) complies with EMVco's rules for EMV transactions. Besides it implements rules and checks for brand specific requirements (e.g. Visa, Mastercard, and many local supported schemes).

Education

Universiteit van Amsterdam Msc, Software Engineering, 2012 - 2016 Hogeschool van Amsterdam B ICT, Computer Science, 2005 - 2010 Marecollege HAVO, N&G, 1999 - 2005

Jeroen Peeters

Software Engineer / Technical Lead

jeroen@peetersweb.nl



Contact Jeroen on LinkedIn